Hi everyone welcome back.
大家好 欢迎回来
So here are my solutions for the subsampling part.
这是我的子采样解决方案
So here I am basically just going to,
我就是
you know just calculate this probability and then scroll through the entire,
计算了这个概率 然后遍历整个
like into words our data set and drop words that are frequent.
int_words 数据集 把一些高频词舍弃掉
So the first thing I did here was
所以我做的第一件事是
calculate the frequencies of all the words in the dataset.
计算数据集所有单词的频率
So to do that, I used a counter and passed it into words
因此我使用了计数器函数 counter 把数据集 int_words 传递给函数
so this counts up all the words in our dataset.
计数器会对数据集的各个单词进行统计
And then we can use this count to actually get the frequencies.
借助这个统计结果 我们就可以得出频率
So the frequencies are you know,
你也知道 频率
like how often these words show up in the total data set.
就是这些单词在整个数据集里出现的频繁程度
And so we can just take our word counts and then
所以我们可以用 word_counts
divide it by a total count which is like the total number of words in our dataset,
除以 total_count 后者是数据集的总单词数
which is not like the number of individual words but they are not
不是各单词出现的次数
the number of unique words but number of individual words in our dataset.
不是不同的单词出现的次数 而是数据集的总单词数
So here I'm using a dictionary comprehension to create
这里我用字典推导式创建了个字典
a dictionary where we can pass in a word and get out the frequency.
我们可以把单词传递给该字典 从而求得频率
So I'm just taking the count for each word and dividing it by the total word count.
所以取各单词的统计结果 将其除以总词数
And we get our our words and our counts from word counts which is our counter,
借助计数器 word_counts 来得到单词及其统计数据
and the items so this just iterates over all the the keys and values in word counts.
这里 .items 指的是函数会遍历 word_counts 里的所有键和值
So the keys are the words and the values are the count of
键指的就是单词 而值就是单词的统计结果
those words and then so we just take count
所以
and divide it by total count and that gives us the frequency of the words in our dataset.
让统计结果除以总词数 求得数据集单词的频率
The next, I find the probability to drop, so basically,
接下来要求舍弃概率
we just scan through like all the words in our frequencies and then just 1 - √t,
所以我们要遍历频率集 freqs 的所有单词 然后代入这条公式
the threshold that we define,
t 是我们定义的阀值
divided by the frequencies.
整个公式就是 1 减阀值除以单词频率的平方根
So here's what I'm doing, so I'm using
所以我用另一个字典推导式
another dictionary comprehension to create a dictionary
再创建一个字典
where the keys are the words and then the values are our probability.
在这个字典里 键也是单词 值则是概率
So one minus the square root of the threshold divided by the frequency of that word.
也即 1 减阀值除以单词频率的平方根
Okay. So now that we have
好了 现在我们有了
the frequencies and the probabilities that we're going to drop it,
频率和舍弃概率
we can go through all the words in int_words in
我们可以遍历 int_words 数据里的所有单词
our data and drop the ones that are frequent.
并舍弃高频单词了
So what I'm doing here is I am scrolling through each of
接着 我要遍历
the words in int_words and I'm looking at the probabilities to drop it,
int_ words 里的每个单词 找出相应的舍弃概率
and comparing that with some randomly generated number.
将该概率与某个随机生成的数字进行比较
So what random.random does is it samples from a uniform distribution between 0 and 1.
所以 random.random 会从一个在 0 和 1 之间的均匀分布中采样
So, the way you think about this is like if the probability
你可以这么想 假设单词舍弃概率是 70%
to drop a word is say 70%, so 0.7.
也就是 0.7
Then we basically just generate a random number from random.random and so there is
而 random.random 生成的随机数
a 70% chance it'll be less than 0.7 and there's a 30% chance it'll be greater than 0.7.
有 70% 的概率小于 0.7 还有 30% 的概率大于 0.7
So then if our probability is less than this randomly
如果舍弃概率小于这个随机生成的数字
generated numbers so if our probability like 0.7 and if it's less than random.random,
假设概率是 0.7 小于 random.random 生成的随机数
so say it's like we actually get you know 0.8 out of here.
比如说这里随机生成了 0.8
So then 0.8 &gt; 0.7,
0.8 大于 0.7
and so then we're going to actually keep the word.
我们就会保留那个单词
But this only happens 30% of the time because this is 0.7 and we're only
但保留的概率只有 30% 因为这是 0.7
going to get a number larger than our drop probability 30% of the time.
而我们能大于舍弃概率的概率就是 30%
So then we're going to keep 30% of the words.
所以我们会保留 30% 的单词
It might also be clear if I write it like this.
如果我这么写 或许能更清楚些
So since this is our probability to drop a word then
这是单词的舍弃概率
one minus this is the probability to keep a word.
1 减去这个概率就是单词的保留概率
So again, if we're generating random number and this is
一样的道理 如果我们生成了随机数
a probability to keep a word so then say like the probability to keep a word is like 60%,
而这是单词保留概率 比如单词的保留概率是 60%
so then 60% of the time we're actually going to
那么有 60% 的可能我们会
generate a random number, and that's less than that.
生成一个小于这个概率的随机数
So, again this is just like
所以
some probabilistic way to use this probability to decide if we keep or drop a word.
这其实就是概率学 我们只是用概率来决定要舍弃还是保留一个单词
And we want this to be probabilistic because we want this to be like uniform,
我们想以概率学的方式来舍弃单词 这样才能对不同的单词一视同仁
unless it's dropping, the sampling to be uniform across the entire dataset.
我们希望整个数据集的采样过程没有特例
So in any batch that you give in you want it to be,
也就是无论输入哪一批
like you want it to have the same probability that,
都能以一定的概率舍弃单词
you know that 'the' was dropped from like
比如让单词 the 在第一批被舍弃的概率
the first batch to like some batch in the middle and the batch at the end.
和在中间以及最后一批被舍弃的概率一样
Hey see in the next video.
好了 下个视频见